<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Let&#x27;s go &quot;My, my!&quot;</title>
    <link href="https://mymy-us.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://mymy-us.github.io" />
    <updated>2026-02-19T18:03:25+08:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Tim Y</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mymy-us.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Translating &quot;Geek Speak&quot; to Business Speak: From Cpk to DPPM</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Y</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://mymy-us.github.io/translating-geek-speak-to-business-speak-from-cpk-to-dppm.html"/>
        <id>https://mymy-us.github.io/translating-geek-speak-to-business-speak-from-cpk-to-dppm.html</id>
            <category term="The Lean Toolkit"/>
            <category term="The Lean Thinking"/>
            <category term="Quality Engineering"/>

        <updated>2025-09-10T18:02:00+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                    Topic: Process Capability &amp; Risk Assessment The Academic View: Calculate $C_{pk}$. If the result is $&gt;1.33$, the process is capable. The Reality: Your&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Topic:</strong> Process Capability &amp; Risk Assessment
<strong>The Academic View:</strong> Calculate $C_{pk}$. If the result is $&gt;1.33$, the process is capable.
<strong>The Reality:</strong> Your boss and the Finance team do not care about the number “1.33.” They care about <strong>Risk</strong> and <strong>Scrap Costs</strong>.</p><p>You need to stop reporting just the index number and start translating it into <strong>DPPM (Defects Per Million)</strong>.</p><h3 id="the-logic-why-convert">The Logic: Why Convert?</h3>
<p>In a boardroom, nobody asks, “What is the standard deviation within the subgroup?”
They ask: <em>“How many bad parts are we going to ship?”</em></p><p>According to the ASQ (American Society for Quality) and standard Six Sigma textbooks, there is a direct mathematical link between your Process Capability ($C_{pk}$) and the probability of a defect.</p><ul>
<li><strong>$C_{pk}$</strong> = How well your process fits inside the goal posts (Specification Limits).</li>
<li><strong>Sigma Level</strong> = The statistical robustness of the process.</li>
<li><strong>DPPM</strong> = The predicted number of failures per million parts produced.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="the-cheat-sheet-short-term-capability">The Cheat Sheet (Short Term Capability)</h3>
<p>Based on standard statistical tables (assuming a centered, normal distribution), here is the translation you need to memorize.</p><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th align="left">Cpk Value</th>
<th align="left">Process Sigma</th>
<th align="left">DPPM (Defects Per Million)</th>
<th align="left">The Reality</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody><tr>
<td align="left"><strong>0.67</strong></td>
<td align="left">2.0 $\sigma$</td>
<td align="left"><strong>45,500</strong></td>
<td align="left"><strong>Disaster.</strong> You are scrapping ~4.5% of your product. You are losing money on every run.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left"><strong>1.00</strong></td>
<td align="left">3.0 $\sigma$</td>
<td align="left"><strong>2,700</strong></td>
<td align="left"><strong>The Danger Zone.</strong> 0.27% defect rate. In the automotive industry, this is often unacceptable.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left"><strong>1.33</strong></td>
<td align="left">4.0 $\sigma$</td>
<td align="left"><strong>63</strong></td>
<td align="left"><strong>The Industry Standard.</strong> This is why 1.33 is the “magic number.” You drop from thousands of defects to just 63.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left"><strong>1.67</strong></td>
<td align="left">5.0 $\sigma$</td>
<td align="left"><strong>0.57</strong></td>
<td align="left"><strong>World Class.</strong> Less than 1 defect per million.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left"><strong>2.00</strong></td>
<td align="left">6.0 $\sigma$</td>
<td align="left"><strong>0.002</strong></td>
<td align="left"><strong>Six Sigma.</strong> Perfection.</td>
</tr>
</tbody></table>
<h3 id="how-to-use-this-in-a-meeting">How to Use This in a Meeting</h3>
<p>Don’t just say: <em>“Our Cpk is 1.0.”</em>
Say: <em>“Our Cpk is 1.0. This predicts we will produce <strong>2,700 defects per million parts</strong>. At our current volume, that is <strong>X</strong> bad parts per week. We need to improve the process to 1.33 to reduce that risk to near zero.”</em></p><h3 id="a-warning-on-sample-size">A Warning on Sample Size</h3>
<p><strong>Garbage In, Garbage Out.</strong>
You cannot calculate a real DPPM from 5 parts.</p><ul>
<li><strong>Academic Math:</strong> You can calculate Standard Deviation with $n=2$.</li>
<li><strong>Business Reality:</strong> To trust the DPPM prediction, you need a significant sample size (usually 30 to 50 parts minimum).</li>
</ul>
<p>If you calculate a $C_{pk}$ of 1.67 based on 5 parts, you are lying to yourself. The sample is too small to predict the long-term behavior of the process.</p><h3 id="the-takeaway">The Takeaway</h3>
<p>$C_{pk}$ is not just a badge of honor for the PPAP file. It is a <strong>Financial Prediction</strong>.</p><ul>
<li>Low $C_{pk}$ = High Defects = High Cost.</li>
<li>High $C_{pk}$ = Low Defects = Low Cost.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Learn to speak the language of Defects (DPPM), and management will listen to your engineering proposals.</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Hidden ROI: Why Operator Happiness is an Engineering Problem</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Y</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://mymy-us.github.io/the-hidden-roi-why-operator-happiness-is-an-engineering-problem.html"/>
        <id>https://mymy-us.github.io/the-hidden-roi-why-operator-happiness-is-an-engineering-problem.html</id>
            <category term="The Lean Thinking"/>

        <updated>2025-09-09T17:50:00+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                    Topic: The Human Element of Lean The Academic View: Operators are “resources.” You calculate their Cycle Time and Ergonomics. If the math works,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Topic:</strong> The Human Element of Lean<br><strong>The Academic View:</strong> Operators are “resources.” You calculate their Cycle Time and Ergonomics. If the math works, the line runs.<br><strong>The Reality:</strong> Operators are the gatekeepers of your success. If they hate the culture, your process will fail, no matter how perfect your engineering is.</p><p>Here is why “treating people well” is a technical requirement, not just an HR slogan.</p><h3 id="1-the-tribal-knowledge-the-8th-waste">1. The “Tribal Knowledge” (The 8th Waste)</h3>
<p>Engineers look at data; Operators look at reality.<br>An operator stands at that machine for 8 to 12 hours a day. You stand there for 10 minutes.</p><ul>
<li><strong>The Gap:</strong> They might not know the engineering terms like “OEE” or “Six Sigma.”</li>
<li><strong>The Gold Mine:</strong> They know exactly which jig is sticky, which tool is heavy, and which sensor glitches every day at 2:00 PM.</li>
<li><strong>The Loss:</strong> If you ignore them because they have “lower education,” you commit the <strong>8th Waste: Non-Utilized Talent</strong>. You miss the root cause because you didn’t ask the only person who sees it happen.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2-the-danger-of-malicious-compliance">2. The Danger of “Malicious Compliance”</h3>
<p>If an operator feels disrespected, they disconnect. They stop caring.</p><ul>
<li><strong>Scenario:</strong> A machine is drifting slightly out of spec, or creating a new characteristic that they do not seem before.</li>
<li><strong>The Respected Operator:</strong> Stops the line, calls you, and prevents a defect.</li>
<li><strong>The Disrespected Operator:</strong> Says, “Not my problem. The boss didn’t ask me.” They let 500 bad parts pass through.</li>
</ul>
<p>Later, when you face a customer complaint, you will wonder why your controls failed. They failed because the human element bypassed them. <strong>You cannot engineer a safeguard against apathy.</strong></p><h3 id="3-the-new-hire-tax-efficiency-loss">3. The “New Hire Tax” (Efficiency Loss)</h3>
<p>Lean relies on stability. High turnover is the enemy of stability.<br>When an operator quits because the work environment is toxic, you pay a heavy tax.</p><p><strong>The Learning Curve Math:</strong></p><ul>
<li><strong>Day 1:</strong> A new hire usually runs at <strong>2.0x Cycle Time</strong> (50% efficiency).</li>
<li><strong>Day 2-3:</strong> They improve to <strong>1.8x Cycle Time</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Week 2:</strong> They might finally hit Standard Rate.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have high turnover, your line is permanently running at 80% efficiency because you are always training someone new.</p><h3 id="4-the-method-how-to-bridge-the-gap">4. The Method: How to bridge the gap</h3>
<p>You are the Engineer. It is your job to build the bridge.</p><ul>
<li><strong>Ask “What,” not “Why”:</strong> Don’t ask “Why are you doing it that way?” (It sounds accusatory). Ask “What makes this step hard to do?”</li>
<li><strong>Fix the Pebble in the Shoe:</strong> If they complain about a flickering light, a sharp edge on a bin, or a missing mat—fix it immediately.</li>
<li><strong>The Result:</strong> When you fix the small things that annoy them, they will trust you with the big things that worry you.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="the-takeaway">The Takeaway</h3>
<p>You can have the best Control Plan in the world, but if the person pushing the button wants you to fail, you will fail.<br><strong>Treat operators like the Subject Matter Experts they are.</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The $1,000 Per Minute Nightmare: Line Stoppages &amp; The Air Freight Trap</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Y</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://mymy-us.github.io/the-1000-per-minute-nightmare-line-stoppages-and-the-air-freight-trap.html"/>
        <id>https://mymy-us.github.io/the-1000-per-minute-nightmare-line-stoppages-and-the-air-freight-trap.html</id>
            <category term="The Lean Toolkit"/>
            <category term="Supply Chain Optimization"/>

        <updated>2025-09-09T17:37:00+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                    Topic: Crisis Management &amp; Supply Chain Strategy The Scenario: A quality defect is found. All inventory at the customer and your warehouse is&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Topic:</strong> Crisis Management &amp; Supply Chain Strategy<br><strong>The Scenario:</strong> A quality defect is found. All inventory at the customer and your warehouse is quarantined (useless). You are at Zero.</p><h3 id="part-1-the-cost-of-silence">Part 1: The Cost of Silence</h3>
<p>In the automotive industry, a “Line Down” situation is the ultimate failure.<br>Production lines are continuous. If one station stops, the whole factory stops.</p><ul>
<li><strong>The Fine:</strong> Penalties often range from <strong>$1,000 to $10,000 per minute</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>The Logistics:</strong> Even if you have the part in your hand at the gate, it might take 20 minutes just to walk through a massive plant (like Tesla or Daimler-Benz) to reach the line. That walk alone costs $20,000+ in fines.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="part-2-the-math-of-the-death-spiral">Part 2: The Math of the “Death Spiral”</h3>
<p>When inventory hits zero, most new engineers think: “I just need to rush parts there today.”<br>Wrong. You are facing a <strong>Pipeline Problem</strong>.</p><p><strong>The Example:</strong></p><ul>
<li><strong>Customer Demand:</strong> 10 parts/day.</li>
<li><strong>Your Max Capacity:</strong> 12 parts/day.</li>
<li><strong>Transit Time (Ocean):</strong> 30 days.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you produce 12 parts today, you must Air Freight them immediately to keep the line running tomorrow.<br><strong>But you can’t stop there.</strong><br>Because the cheaper option (Ocean Freight) takes 30 days, you must Air Freight your daily production <strong>every single day for 30 days</strong> until the first boat shipment arrives.</p><p><strong>The Result:</strong> You are paying premium freight for a whole month. This usually costs more than <strong>50% of the total failure cost</strong>. It wipes out the profit margin for the entire year.</p><h3 id="part-3-the-solution-postponement-localization--tooling">Part 3: The Solution (Postponement, Localization &amp; Tooling)</h3>
<p>How do we prevent this without spending a fortune?<br>We cannot always move the whole factory from a low-cost country (like China or Vietnam) to the US. Labor is too expensive.</p><p>The answer is <strong>Strategic Postponement</strong> (or Near-shoring).</p><p><strong>1. The “Final Assembly” Node</strong><br>Keep the complex, labor-intensive fabrication in the low-cost country.<br>Move the final, simple steps (packaging, labeling, light assembly) to a location near the customer (e.g., a US subsidiary or a Mexico border facility).</p><ul>
<li><strong>Routine:</strong> Ship semi-finished parts via cheap Ocean Freight to the local node.</li>
<li><strong>Crisis:</strong> If a defect is found, your inventory is already local. You can purge, rework, or finish new parts in <strong>hours</strong>, not weeks.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>2. The Forward Stocking Location (3PL)</strong><br>If you can’t build a factory, rent a warehouse.<br>Use a Third-Party Logistics (3PL) provider near the customer to hold 2 weeks of “Safety Stock.”</p><ul>
<li><strong>Lean Counter-point:</strong> Yes, Lean says inventory is waste.</li>
<li><strong>Business Reality:</strong> Paying for 2 weeks of storage is “Waste.” But paying for 4 weeks of Air Freight is “Disaster.” Pick the cheaper waste.</li>
</ul>
<p> <strong>3. Redundant Tooling (The Backup Plan)</strong>
 If you cannot move assembly, you must have <strong>Redundant Tooling</strong>.<br>Don’t keep all your molds/dies in one factory. If a mold breaks or a quality issue is tied to a specific machine, you need a backup set of tooling ready to run at a different location immediately.</p><h3 id="the-takeaway">The Takeaway</h3>
<p>Supply Chain optimization isn’t just about the “lowest piece price.”<br>It is about <strong>Recovery Speed</strong>.<br>If your factory is 30 days away from your customer, you are one quality spill away from bankruptcy. <strong>Shorten the distance.</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>PPAP: It’s Not Just Paperwork, It’s Your Legal Shield</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Y</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://mymy-us.github.io/ppap-its-not-just-paperwork-its-your-legal-shield.html"/>
        <id>https://mymy-us.github.io/ppap-its-not-just-paperwork-its-your-legal-shield.html</id>
            <category term="The Lean Thinking"/>

        <updated>2025-09-07T17:02:00+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                    Topic: The True Purpose of PPAP (Production Part Approval Process) The Academic View: PPAP demonstrates that a supplier can meet manufacturing requirements at&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Topic:</strong> The True Purpose of PPAP (Production Part Approval Process)<br><strong>The Academic View:</strong> PPAP demonstrates that a supplier can meet manufacturing requirements at the quoted production rate.<br><strong>The Reality:</strong> PPAP is a <strong>Legal Contract</strong>. It is the “Constitution” of your product.</p><p>Here is why you need to treat it like a weapon, not a checklist.</p><h3 id="1-the-shield-protecting-your-company">1. The Shield: Protecting Your Company</h3>
<p>Once the customer signs the <strong>PSW (Part Submission Warrant)</strong>, the rules are frozen.</p><p><strong>The Scenario:</strong><br>You are six months into mass production. The customer complains that the surface texture is “too rough” or the color is “slightly off.”</p><p><strong>The Defense:</strong><br>You pull out the approved PPAP and the “Master Sample” (the physical part they signed).</p><ul>
<li><strong>If your current parts match the Master Sample:</strong> You are safe. The customer agreed to this standard. If they want to change it now, <strong>they must pay for it</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>If you don’t have a signed PPAP:</strong> The customer can change their mind daily, and you have to pay for the rework.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Key Lesson:</strong> The signed PSW protects you from the customer’s changing opinions.</p><h3 id="2-the-trap-the-cycle-time-lie">2. The Trap: The “Cycle Time” Lie</h3>
<p>This is where Lean Engineers get burned.<br>In the PPAP, you document your <strong>Cycle Time</strong> (e.g., 60 seconds per part).</p><ul>
<li><strong>Do not cheat here.</strong></li>
<li>Do not run the machine slow just to get good parts for the sample.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you PPAP at 60 seconds but run Mass Production at 45 seconds to make more money, you have committed a <strong>Process Violation</strong>. If quality issues appear later, the customer will void your approval because you are running a different process than the one they approved.</p><h3 id="3-the-warning-unapproved-changes">3. The Warning: Unapproved Changes</h3>
<p>This is the “Third Rail”—touch it and you die.</p><p>If you change anything in the process after the PPAP is signed, you must tell the customer.</p><ul>
<li>Changing a cutting tool brand? <strong>Notify them.</strong></li>
<li>Moving the machine to a different spot on the floor? <strong>Notify them.</strong></li>
<li>Reducing inspection frequency? <strong>Notify them.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>If you make a change without approval (even if it makes the part better), and a recall happens:</p><ol>
<li><strong>You are liable.</strong> The lawyers will see you didn’t follow the PPAP.</li>
<li><strong>You lose your certification (IATF 16949).</strong></li>
<li><strong>Your company faces massive fines.</strong></li>
</ol>
<h3 id="the-takeaway">The Takeaway</h3>
<p>Don’t copy-paste your PPAP documents just to get it done.</p><ul>
<li><strong>Be Honest:</strong> Only promise a cycle time and tolerance you can actually hit every day.</li>
<li><strong>Be Strict:</strong> Once it is signed, the factory floor must follow it exactly.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Treat the PPAP like a court testimony. Because one day, it might be the only thing standing between you and a million-dollar fine.</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Two Halves of Your Lean Job (And Why the Second Half is Harder)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Y</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://mymy-us.github.io/the-two-halves-of-your-lean-job-and-why-the-second-half-is-harder.html"/>
        <id>https://mymy-us.github.io/the-two-halves-of-your-lean-job-and-why-the-second-half-is-harder.html</id>
            <category term="The Lean Thinking"/>

        <updated>2025-09-07T16:46:00+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                    Topic: The Reality of a Lean Engineer’s Role The Trap: Thinking your job is just “fixing things.” If you ask a professor what&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Topic:</strong> The Reality of a Lean Engineer’s Role<br><strong>The Trap:</strong> Thinking your job is just “fixing things.”</p><p>If you ask a professor what a Lean Engineer does, they’ll say: “Continuous Improvement.”<br>If you ask me, I’ll tell you the job is actually two distinct battles:</p><ol>
<li><strong>The Attack:</strong> Continuously Eliminating Waste.</li>
<li><strong>The Defense:</strong> Sustaining the Gains.</li>
</ol>
<p>Most new grads crush the first part and fail the second. Here is why.</p><hr>
<h3 id="phase-1-the-maverick-the-attack">Phase 1: The Maverick (The Attack)</h3>
<p>This is the fun part. You are the detective.</p><p>You walk onto the floor, clipboard in hand, looking for Shingo’s <strong>7 Wastes</strong> (Defects, Overproduction, Waiting, etc.) plus the deadliest one: <strong>The Waste of Human Talent/Ideas.</strong></p><p>In this phase, you can be a <strong>Maverick</strong>. You can run the data, identify the bottleneck, and design a fix all by yourself. You are the hero with the spreadsheet.</p><p><strong>The result:</strong> You save the company money. You feel like a genius.</p><hr>
<h3 id="phase-2-the-politician-the-defense">Phase 2: The Politician (The Defense)</h3>
<p>This is where the “Introvert Tax” hits hard.</p><p>You improved the process. Great. Now, how do you make sure the operators don’t go back to the old way the second you leave the room?</p><p><strong>The “Paper Shield” is Weak</strong><br>In school, they teach you to update the documentation:</p><ul>
<li>Control Plans</li>
<li>Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs)</li>
<li>Publishing via the PLM (Product Lifecycle Management) system</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The Reality:</strong> Documents are passive. They live on servers. To sustain change, you need <strong>Active Enforcement</strong>:</p><ol>
<li><strong>Visual Management:</strong> Don’t just write a rule; put tape on the floor or a shadow board on the wall. Make it impossible to ignore.</li>
<li><strong>LPA (Layered Process Audits):</strong> If management doesn’t check it, operators won’t do it.</li>
<li><strong>Gemba Walks:</strong> You need to be seen on the floor, verifying the fix.</li>
</ol>
<p>But even with these tools, you need <strong>Influence</strong>.</p><hr>
<h3 id="the-owner-mindset">The “Owner” Mindset</h3>
<p>To survive Phase 2, you need to drop the “I’m just a new grad” attitude.</p><p>You need to walk into the Kaizen project with absolute, unwavering confidence. You need the attitude of:</p><blockquote>
<p>“I am the Subject Matter Expert. Nobody knows this data better than
me.”</p></blockquote>
<p>It sounds arrogant? Good.<br>If you are leading a change, you are the <strong>de facto leader</strong> in that room.</p><ul>
<li><strong>Don’t</strong> sit in the back corner of the meeting.</li>
<li><strong>Don’t</strong> be afraid of the Production Manager.</li>
<li><strong>Do</strong> speak first. Frame the problem. Own the solution.</li>
<li><strong>Do</strong> actively seek helps from your own department.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="how-to-win-the-turf-war">How to Win the “Turf War”</h3>
<p>You cannot order people from other departments to listen to you. You have no authority over them.</p><p>You have to use <strong>“The Borrowed Sword.”</strong></p><ol>
<li><strong>Find the Department Head:</strong> The person who actually owns the staff you are trying to change.</li>
<li><strong>Sell the Benefit (WIIFM):</strong> Don’t tell them “It’s Lean.” Tell them, “This change will save your team 20 hours of overtime a month.”</li>
<li><strong>Get the Endorsement:</strong> Once the Department Head sees the benefit, ask them to announce it.</li>
</ol>
<p>When the boss says, “We are doing this,” the team follows. You are just the architect; let the Department Head be the enforcer.</p><h3 id="the-takeaway">The Takeaway</h3>
<p><strong>Phase 1 (Fixing)</strong> requires IQ.<br><strong>Phase 2 (Sustaining)</strong> requires EQ (Emotional Intelligence) and Guts.</p><p>Don’t just be a smart engineer. Be a loud one.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>De-escalation: The Ultimate Mindset to Solve a Complaint</title>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Y</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://mymy-us.github.io/the-art-of-de-escalation-saving-money-and-face-2.html"/>
        <id>https://mymy-us.github.io/the-art-of-de-escalation-saving-money-and-face-2.html</id>
            <category term="The Lean Toolkit"/>
            <category term="Quality Engineering"/>

        <updated>2025-09-06T16:03:00+08:00</updated>
            <summary type="html">
                <![CDATA[
                    Topic: Handling Customer Complaints The Academic View: “The Voice of the Customer is sacred. Whatever they ask for, do it.” The Reality: The&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><strong>Topic</strong>: Handling Customer Complaints
<strong>The Academic View</strong>: “The Voice of the Customer is sacred. Whatever they ask for, do it.”
<strong>The Reality</strong>: The customer’s “wants” are a bottomless pit that will bankrupt you.</p><h3 id="the-golden-rule">The Golden Rule</h3>
<p>In Cantonese, there is a saying that perfectly describes the life of a Quality Engineer:</p><div style="text-align: center;"> <img loading="lazy" src="大事化小，小事化無.jpg" alt="大事化小，小事化無" width="400" data-is-external-image="true"> </div>

<p>Translation: “Make big problems small, and make small problems disappear.”</p><p>This is the art of <span style="color: #920D14;"><em><strong>De-escalation</strong></em></span>.</p><h3 id="the-trap-the-perfect-solution">The Trap: “The Perfect Solution”</h3>
<p>When a defect happens, the customer (usually an SQE - Supplier Quality Engineer) naturally panics. They demand the moon: 100% third-party sorting, brand new tooling, air freight, and a 50-page report.</p><p>If you say “Yes” to everything, you fail.</p><ul>
<li><strong>The Cost</strong>: Your company eats the bill for sorting and rework.</li>
<li><strong>The Precedent</strong>: You teach the customer that they can bully you every time.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="the-psychology-of-your-counterpart">The Psychology of Your Counterpart</h3>
<p>To win, you have to understand who you are talking to. The SQE on the other side isn’t evil. They are just having a really bad day:</p><ol>
<li><strong>Their Production Team</strong> is yelling at them because the line stopped.</li>
<li><strong>Their Boss</strong> is asking for a report.</li>
<li><strong>They are scared</strong> they can’t handle it.</li>
</ol>
<p>Key Insight: If they feel like they can’t handle the issue, they will <em><strong>Escalate</strong></em>.
Escalation = Management gets involved = Trust goes down = Future business is lost.</p><p>Your job isn’t just to fix the part. It is to <strong>make the SQE feel safe</strong> so they don’t hit the panic button.</p><h3 id="the-playbook-how-to-de-escalate">The Playbook: How to De-escalate</h3>
<p> <strong>Internal Rule #1:</strong>
<strong>Never lie to yourself.</strong> Internally, you must find the true Root Cause, fix the process, and update the control plan. If you don’t fix it, the problem comes back, and you die.</p><p><strong>External Rule #2:</strong><br><strong>Filter the noise.</strong> Once the internal fix is solid, your communication strategy changes based on the severity.</p><p><span style="font-size: 0.8em;"><strong>Scenario A: The “Small” Thing (Low Risk/Low FMEA score)</strong></span></p><ul>
<li>The Situation: A minor cosmetic defect or a one-off glitch.</li>
<li>The Goal: Make it disappear (“let it go”).</li>
<li>The Move: Leverage your relationship. Show them the data.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>“Hey, looking at the FMEA, the risk is negligible. We’ve already
implemented [Fix X] internally so it won’t happen again. Let’s treat
this as an isolated incident. No need for third-party sorting.”</p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-size: 0.8em;"><strong>Scenario A: The “Small” Thing (Low Risk/Low FMEA score)</strong></span></p><ul>
<li>The Situation: It’s bad.</li>
<li>The Goal: Make it small.</li>
<li>The Move: Provide an “Easy Button.”<ul>
<li>Don’t let them panic about air freight or line-down.</li>
<li>Give them a containment plan immediately that makes them look good to their boss.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>“We have a containment team ready. Here is the immediate clean point.
You don’t need to stop the line; we have you covered.”</p></blockquote>
<h3 id="lean-corner-why-this-is-technical-not-just-political">Lean Corner: Why this is Technical, not just Political</h3>
<p>You might think, “Tim, isn’t this just playing politics?”<br>No. This is <strong>Lean Manufacturing</strong>.</p><p>One of the deadly wastes in Lean is <strong>Over-processing</strong> (doing more work than the customer actually needs).</p><ul>
<li><strong>Reactive Engineering:</strong> The customer yells -&gt; You panic -&gt; You spend $10k on air freight for a $50 issue. <strong>(Waste)</strong></li>
<li><strong>Lean Engineering:</strong> You analyze the risk -&gt; You prove the process is safe -&gt; You ship standard ground. <strong>(Value)</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>De-escalation isn’t about hiding problems. It’s about Confidence. <strong>Don’t let panic create waste.</strong>
<strong>Fix the part. Manage the panic. Save the money.</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
